me I'll get you another salesman if it's
the car if it's the color if it's you
know what I mean there's always
something there's always something
there if it's too much money we can look
at something cheaper or you know
whatever the case is so yeah you know
like uh the one of the lessons I learned
was commitment you know really asking
people for the commitment getting them
to say yes as much times as possible
because even the commitment of do you
want to come in or you know Mr keser how
can I earn your business I I you know
those were for me being an entrepreneur
that those lessons have served me
greatly you know because it's really
hard to ask people for money right you
know but people just want to get it done
like people are like I want to buy I
want to buy it now what do I need to do
but then you're
like I don't know like you know you can
come back another time you know you just
have to be straight up it's like you
know I would rather them walk then me
not say anything and them walk out
because yeah when people are in that
buying
mode they're going to go on to the next
dealership and they're going to buy a
car yep absolutely that is so
unfortunate well they say statistics are
people usually buy a car within 74 72
hours with hitting their lot the first
time so I mean that's that's a lot
that's that's a high so I mean as soon
as they leave your dealership if they
don't leave in a car I mean the
statistics are you know they're most
likely they're not going to come back so
you got to have the mentality of like
they're never going to come back to to
your
dealership you know once they leave I
mean some come back obviously but a lot
of times they don't and they go down the
street because they met a Salesman that
they like better or you know they had a
different whatever the case is so you
that's why when they're there you gota
you know you got to treat them right and
you yeah are you a
workaholic I would say my boss says no
sometimes
but I I'm uh it's the community aspect
of things and um you you guys can create
content for the hustle Zone like see all
those little videos that started off at
the at the beginning of the show if you
want to do a 50- second video of one
thing that's motivational that will get
people going uh make sure you got great
lighting make sure you got a good good
audio Source or like you know make sure
you're just in a good situation um you
know submit that stuff to me and in HD
maybe in Dropbox and I'll get you guys
going and then you guys will be on the
website and all that stuff when it
launches so uh we definitely we
definitely want to um uh we definitely
want to get uh you guys participating in
that and tomorrow's show we have a lease
with being nice matters so we definitely
want you guys to check that out at 100
p.m. so 1 p.m. Mountain Standard Time
folks so today's guest really excited
for for this today's guest because you
know he's been a you know he's been a
supporter of the show and you know uh
also a potential client and also just a
friend just someone that's been looking
out uh he he is uh he is the top
salesperson uh for uh Dave Sinclair Ford
he sold over 200 vehicles in
2016 you know I remember when I was in
car sales I only sold 10 in one month
man I can't imagine selling 200 but you
know the thing about the card business
that I understand is that it's longevity
it's not quitting at all
like you know you don't quit you stay in
the game for about three years because
people are going to start turning over
they're going to start coming back and
doing business with you you know when I
was in the one thing I would mention is
that when I was in um Car Sales I I came
from cell phone sales and I when I
people come into the store I be like H
my name is Ryan Perez how you doing blah
blah blah blah blah right in their face
and my car salesperson was like bro
you're not selling snake oil okay he's
like you got to you got to soften the
voice so I learned how to soften my
voice like hi my name is Ryan Perez how
can I help you you know so I you know I
was dressed up in a nice suit I didn't
have a bow tie on at the time but you
know a guy people through the cars and
then you know the greatest feeling at
the end of the day was doing that
delivery like giving away that car and
letting them drive off in that car I
sold my sister a car she still has it
it's it's it's amazing but it the whole
thing is like you know it just feels
great when you close that sale because
you don't get paid until the sale is
delivered so
anyway this is a hustler he's a true
Hustler I mean um and he's really quiet
you know he has a he's quite demeanor
not quite but he's just you know he's
lowkey he has a beautiful family he's a
Family Guy and um I want to welcome you
guys Scott Brun how are you doing my
friend Hi everybody how's it going it's
going all right so you finally made it
onto the hustle Zone hey finally after
all this time watching this show I
finally get to get a spot here so I'm
excited well you're the you're the OG
man I think that once this show gets to
the next level I mean you're going to be
like it's it's funny because when you
look at like like TV shows or like
movements back in the days they always
started off with this community coming
together and then all the people just
went off to do really great things and I
think this is what this hustle zone is
going to do I think that everyone's
going to go off and do good things you
know what I
Meely I totally agree so um so welcome
so thank normally the so I have to
explain uh normally the hustle Zone like
everyone always ask me what's the hustle
Zone well the hustle zone is uh it is a
uh a program where we interview
entrepreneurs uh and people like
entrepreneurs can mean many different
things but we interv interview
entrepreneurs we try to get the story
not the glory you know a lot of people
like to push on all the things that
they've accomplished but I want to know
what happened before that you know I
want you to explain so you have full
domain to talk as much as you want as
deep as you want um and uh we we want to
demonstrate to people that you know
we're all human you know we're all the
same we just have different
habits and if we change our habits we
can have different results the
definition of ins Sand's doing something
over and over again and expecting
different results so you have to we have
to learn to change our habits so uh the
first question I would not people would
get mad at me if I didn't ask first
question is what is your your story and
again free domain you got all day
absolutely no so I actually have a
pretty good story about how I got
started into the car business I um i'
hadd lost my job or got fired somewhere
I forget what I was doing before and my
car broke down and I didn't have enough
money to get my car fixed so I'm like H
why don't I just um I heard that car
dealerships give free demo cars to
people that work for them so I walked
across the highway which is a busy
highway here in St Louis um across I
270 over to this car dealership and um
walked right in applied they make you
take this little test to see if you're
up to sales it's kind of this aptitude
test kind of
deal and um so next thing I know I get a
call saying uh can you can you come in
for an official interview I'm like sure
so I came in they hired me a couple
weeks later I um I had I had my demo car
and I didn't have to pay for Wheels
anymore
so that's how got started in the car
business kind of a crazy story oh if it
wasn't for my car breaking down I don't
know that i' have done
it um so but I'm glad I did and um it's
been very good ride I mean I the car
business has blessed me Beyond Bel it's
provided for my family for a while and
um yeah so uh you're your demeanor
you're you like your demeanor is really
serious yeah very calm um and anytime I
think about sales I've always been
around sales and and people have really
dominant personalities but your your
personality is not like it's not
aggressive so how the hell did you make
it in car sales well actually it's funny
you say that because I get that all the
time they're like well you don't seem
like a typical car salesman I I treat
people like we're sitting at the bar
having a beer or sitting at our my table
you know just just kicking back you know
talking about buying a car you you know
or you know talking about the deal or
about their family or about their life
so it's not and people when they leave
they're like wow this was the best car
buying experience I ever had you know I
don't you know I just treat him like a
normal human being not not a walking
dollar sign that some people like to you
know it's all about it's all about the
relationship it's all about the
relationship yeah because you know like
I don't want to go like people don't
want to be sold to you know they want to
sell themselves into a car and exactly
you know and that's kind of what what
story that I was explaining earlier is
that like you know just having that
sales manager um tell me like hey Ryan
like cool down on the the I think I know
it all you know right
energy totally I mean that's that's a if
you walk into just a normal dealership
off the street and you walk in they most
of the sales people have that mentality
yeah so kind of some of those people
when they see somebody like me that's
not like you know beating them down
trying to get them to you know oh you
gotta do this right right here right now
y y so okay I lost your picture there
uh did you get a notification or
something yeah hold on just a second
here let me get rid of this
okay so when
um when
you tell me a little bit about your
um um
your upbringing like where did you grow
up and you know how was your par how was
the parents and you know yeah yeah I
grew up in a small well it's not small
now but when I was growing up it's a
small town in um outside of about 40
minutes to 45 minutes outside of St
Lewis on Washington
Missouri um I grew up really grew up out
in the country so I kind of grew up on
you know around the farm and all that
stuff out in the middle of nowhere um my
mom at home um my dad worked uh he was a
uh he's a concrete guy M did concrete
work foundations you know that kind of
stuff so he worked he worked his butt
off so hard his whole life I mean I've
seen him go through so like back
problems because that's I mean been and
over that's hard work and I always told
myself I said there's no way I want to
ever be in that type of business I mean
physical business because he went
through so many issues with that I got
to be another way to to do it so
M and um like how did that make you
feel you mean watching him on work all
those years yeah I mean I didn't I
didn't like it at all I mean I it was
really tough on him and really hard on
his and on his body and you can really
see the after effects now that he's
older um so I always what kind of After
Effects like what like what what H like
did he did he just aged
yeah or yeah know your I mean your
joints are I mean that's like really
really bad all the time and you have
constant back problems and you know
constant you know strain on your body
from all the all that heavy lifting and
you know hard work so those guys are out
there busting it every day doing that I
give them definitely props yeah that's
hardcore
work so when you um do you have like do
you do you have uh uh siblings
yes I actually have um three brothers
and two sisters and how did how did they
feel about your dad working so
much um you know I think they just kind
of accepted it um they're all younger
than my than me so um they pretty much
just accepted it and went about about
life but you know I and another thing
too I always told myself you know he was
gone all the time so I told myself I
want to be home more with my son because
I want him to grow up you know with with
me around right so that that's a big
thing I know you you have the same deal
that you always do with your son so yeah
yeah because children are children are
important and I mean I knew what it was
like not to you know like a typical
story of me not growing up with my dad
and
um I think that
um when that when that when that happens
it just you know there's there's there's
there's just stuff that's missing right
because there's lot things that you want
to do you want to go you know to the
movies or you want to go skating and you
can't you know um you know for there's
just so many things and then just
watching your parents just struggle it's
really hard because as kids definitely
we don't really know how to you know
what to do we feel helpless totally and
that and that relationship was
everything and as they get older you
know they'll they they can confide in
you and talk to you and I mean it's
you
know when when you're yeah yeah so um
that being said you know with your with
your son how like what what what is your
vision for your son him being two years
old right and you know the limit is the
sky at this point but totally what what
um what is the vision for your
son well like you know I I try to just
let him do his own thing and let him
make his own decisions I try I try not
to I kind of just try to guide him in
the right direction but I don't want to
put any limits on them because I I want
his mind to be
fully I guess I want to say adjusted to
you know what what he's thinking in his
mind as far as like if he wants to be an
entrepreneur if he wants to do sales if
he wants to do hard labor I mean
whatever you know whatever he decides he
wants to do when he gets older but I I'm
just going to I'm going to let him know
that he can do anything he wants and
even if even if it sounds absurd to
every everybody else or to me I'm going
be like that's what you want to do you
know keep your mind open and you know
fowl forward that's so so what if he
says Dad I want to be a
janitor hey that's what he wants to do I
support him 100 per. yeah that's that's
them man now um how are you with
money what's uh your what's your
perspective on
money I I I don't believe in a lot of
Vin
yeah uh I believe that um you know I try
to put my money elsewhere other than an
actual
bank um to me the F you know the fbic is
just a a stamp I don't believe you know
in anything that you know the government
tries to throw on there anymore you know
it's just pretty much my own I'm in it
for myself you
know I try to save we try to save as
much as we can my wife's a stay-at-home
mom so obviously we got gotta make
everything work here so you got to make
everything count now the camera has
shifted a little bit could you adjust it
a little bit um just one second there we
go stop and then if you could bring it
down a little bit if you so there's no
white
space yeah thanks a lot man yeah so
you're trying to save as much um and do
you believe in investing do you believe
in and um you know what kind of like
what does investing mean to you
investing is definitely um something
that you know I like we have a you know
like we have the typical things that
work you know 401K you know that kind of
thing but you know who knows where
things are going to be in you know 20 30
years whenever you know I retire so I
gotta make my money
count
um when when do you think you're going
to
retire gosh I'm hoping to retire
um I don't know that's a good question I
I ask myself that a lot I'm hoping to be
in the you know 55 to 60 range you know
may maybe sooner if I
can get my investments rolling yeah for
sure and um and because the reason why I
asked this I mean because like a lot of
us like entrepreneurs a lot of us just
think we have we always have to hustle
you know there has to be a point in our
lives where we just stop hustling right
and
let let let our money hustle for
ourselves you know what I mean um so I
honestly think that we like you know
like because I don't know have you ever
read Rich Dad Poor Dad I have not read
that one no oh beautiful book but he he
just talks about assets and liabilities
and how you know an income and expenses
he has this uh little uh this this grid
but he just shows you it's that you know
the more you invest in assets the more
it pays you and it's passive income so
it's kind of like you know investing in
ourselves gets us to the next level uh
but we obviously we all have to make
that money we do need that Nest EG and
right speaking of which it's so what
makes you the top seller at uh at at for
like what makes you or at one of the
four dealerships like what what
uh what habits did you pick
up that allowed you to be where you are
now absolutely so I mean you got to be
ready to hit the ground running as soon
as you get in I mean you got to be ready
to you know to hustle to help people
right away um get on the phone do your
followup work um it's pretty much just
all about you know taking care of the
people working your referral base
working your previous customer base and
just branching out you know to get those
leads and to get those you know extra
extra customers that are sitting out
there because each person that buys from
you knows at least one or two people
probably that need a car right you know
so you just you have basically just have
to say Hey you know if you send somebody
my way I'll you know we have what we
call a bird dog program most of people
that are familiar with the car business
knows about bird dogs they um it's a
referral fee that we pay if you if you
send somebody in and um you know a lot
of people like an extra 50 hundred bucks
or whatever it is they're all different
around the the b car business but um you
little incentive for them to send
somebody your way was it an easy
transition for you when you started in
the car business like was it like cuz CU
I meant I I I like I had two two months
they paid me a wage yeah third month
that was horrible yeah you know to know
that you weren't going to get any income
because at that time I was used to
working for somebody else so right how
did you like when you started how did
you adjust and did you have any
downfalls like tell us the pitfalls we
all want to know the juicy details yeah
absolutely no
so the first couple years you know
I strugg struggled you know kind of just
hopped along a little bit here or there
um and luckily I you know one of the key
things here too is to is to find a
mentor you know a mentor that you can
get behind that that sells a lot you
know and just kind of listen to what
they say listen to how they interact
with the customer and what they do and
pick up those you know just pick up
those some of those good habits you know
they say you're like the the five most
people you hang around with well if
you're hanging out with dead beats all
the time you're not going to do anything
they could care less you know about
providing for their family or you know
what I mean
so um so Bas so that really um just
getting a mentor and you know kind of
following in the steps and then picking
up your personality and kind of
intermingling intertwining it into you
know you yeah did you have a lot of
competition at the beginning did were a
lot of the old dogs you know cuz I had
that happen people are like yeah you
know what
shny right you know they're all like
sitting watching you and they're really
quick to steal your lead and all that
stuff but so how did give me a story no
yeah they um yeah so they're always yeah
they're always trying to be like oh you
know you can't do this you know you can
always go somewhere else and work you
know it's they're not how do I put how
do I say this here they're more of a um
very the old dogs were fairly negative
when I first started in you know they're
like just grabby and you know drink the
coffee stay out of their way don't take
their customers you know even when
they're they're the dealership's
customers or you know whatever when you
first start off but
yeah yeah so that's I mean I don't
really have an actual story per se on
that but that's kind
of how was it to get like were you ever
did you were you ever brought into the
you know the sales room and you know and
had that Dreadful conversation with the
sales manager or the floor manager about
not hitting targets and oh yeah couple
times yeah they're like well M Mr Braun
you're G to have to um step your game up
a little bit you know we know you got
you know they're always like we know you
have it we know you got it in you and
like well you know they just you know I
think a lot of it has to do on maturity
too and you know how you feel about if
you still live at home or if you know
you're you're out and about or if you
have your own own house or place or
whatever depending on that that makes a
big difference on how much you hustle
too sometimes some people just don't
care right but if you know if you need
the money and you're out there I mean
you're going to you're going to go out
and hustle so with that being said what
are some of the things a lot of the
young Hustlers you know the the young
guys that come in here because you know
a lot of piss and finger is like yeah
man I can sell this I can do that I can
sell this and you know you're sitting
there watching some of these guys crash
because a lot of people in this business
Crash and Burn you know what I mean Car
Sales is it's entrepreneurial because
you honestly have to have adopt really a
really good mindset to to keep yourself
through so what were some examples or of
of young guys that you seen come come
your
way I've seen I've seen a lot of people
come and go where we work I mean the car
business as you probably know has a ton
of turnover so there's been a ton of
people come and go but if you got to
hire about 10 to get one or two to stay
generally because living on zero commiss
you know you may you start off at zero
every single month you know you don't
have this rolling paycheck that comes in
every single month being on commission
so you know that either going to make it
or break it so the young guys I mean
I've seen we got a couple guys there now
that you know young guys that are just
um coming in you know they're getting
off their butt they're going out waiting
on people they're you know getting the
phones up PO calling you know whatever
it is whatever it takes and they're
they're doing very well MH
a lot of a lot of the young guys a lot
of the a lot of the Millennials are
doing that and they're um a lot of those
are coming in coming in hot too
so so would you say that you're highly
intelligent or you're just was it just
basic common sense that make you adapt
to that situation like where did you get
the knowhow like is it your personality
you know because it seemed like you fit
in pretty well when you started working
it seemed like you didn't have like much
or maybe I'm wrong I don't know like it
it's coming across as if though you
didn't really have much barriers to your
learning
progression I'm the kind of person that
that easily adapts to my situation I
mean I can you know I can make pretty
much any situation work out pretty well
um you know like like I said it's just
about getting in there building the
relationships with your teammates with
your sales managers with your Finance
managers and you know we've become good
friends you know over the years you know
hanging out that kind of stuff so that I
mean I would say that my you know as far
as my personality goes I'm say I'm very
adaptable you're very adap yeah I mean
am I I think I'm semi intelligent I mean
I'm I think I'm really good with um you
know with with people in general
you is is it hard to go out and wait on
somebody that you just haven't met I
mean yeah every day you know you gota
you got to deal with that you you got to
go out and meet somebody new you got to
go out and talk to somebody you got to
go out and find about a little bit about
their life and a little bit about this
and a little bit about that and you and
then you know you know
it's some people that's hard for you
know some people are introverted some
people are extroverted i' say I'm I'm
both I mean I know it's you know some
people say oh you're either one or
you're the other well I think I'm both
you know I think I'm very introverted
and I think I'm very extroverted it kind
of just depends on where I'm at make I
can make myself
be very extroverted if I you know if I
need to you know what I mean yeah did
you always have this this money-making
you know ideology like just going after
it like when you were a kid like how how
was school did you did you fit it like
before you answer that first question
like how was school how did you grow up
you know did you fit in with the crowd
were you a loner were you the guy that
floated around like how did you you know
adapt in your childhood oh yeah I was uh
I would say I floated around a little
bit you know floated around from here to
there um I always had a hunger though to
to to strive to be better to strive to
make more money strive to be better than
my parent you know my dad my parents all
that stuff um so we didn't have to you
know I wouldn't say we struggled I mean
you know but
um we uh you know we we always had food
on our table and we were always blessed
so I guess there was never really much
struggle there so
but yeah I don't know
it's I fit in pretty I fit in pretty
well yeah the day what what kind of
challenges do you could you say that
you've dealt with that has really um and
and were those
challenges um did they did you
incorporate those challenges in your
everyday
hustle I absolutely had to I like I um
like I said earlier we I had to get over
the fear of just walking out and talk
you know going out and talking to
somebody new every single day so I mean
it's I knew that it was I know that it's
not harder than like I know if I just go
out there you know they'll be nice you
know we'll hit it off y y but I just had
to kind of tell myself that every single
every single time went out you know put
a smile on my face go out there and you
being repetitive go out and doing the
same thing over and over and over and
you know eventually you're going to be
you're going to get it down you're going
to be good at it and if you were to like
like what would be the the main uh
things that you would tell someone when
they come into the car business or if in
sales in general like what would be the
three main you know points to tell them
because I know that you're a floor
manager and yeah you know I'm sure that
you have to have these discussions with
people all the time
like what what's the the major thing
that you say well there's a couple of
major things I tell a lot of the sales
people to just shut up and like one of
my one of my one of my mentors used to
say this he used to he used to always
say that um get out of their get out of
the customer's way and let them buy a
car a lot of salesmen will get in the
way of not not physically in the way but
they'll like get in the way by trying to
talk so much and tell them stuff you
know and kind of pushes pushes the
customer away so just get out of their
way and let them buy a car cuz that's
obviously what they came in there to do
don't put up all these objections that
you can't overcome and then you know
what I
mean it just creates a lot of um you
know a lot of problems and and another
thing that I would say too and this is
this is mostly for the
salesperson some salese are too nice you
know you know what I mean when you're
going when you're trying to close a deal
and you're too
nice I mean they're just like okay well
we'll let you know you don't that's not
what you that's not the answer you want
to hear yeah you know I mean you got to
you you got to go in and you gota you
know be a little bit tough you got to
put on your thick skin get in there and
like hey you know there's there's always
an objection somewhere down you just got
to find out what that one or two or
three or whatever it is objection and
once you find that objection you can go
back and
clarify you know what the objection is
and then go back to go back to closing
and get it you know because there's
there's a reason why they don't want to
buy a car from you but most salespeople
usually say it's either me it's the
money or some people say the machine so
obviously the car in this case so you
just got to find out what the if it's me
I'll get you another salesman if it's
the car if it's the color if it's you
know what I mean there's always some
there's always something
there if it's too much money we can look
at something cheaper or you know
whatever the case is so yeah you know
like uh the one of the lessons I learned
was Comm commitment you know really
asking people for the commitment getting
them to say yes as much times as
possible because even the commitment of
do you want to come in or you know Mr
keser how can I earn your business I I
you know those were for me being an
entrepreneur that those lessons have
served me greatly you know because it's
really hard to ask people for money
right you know but people just want to
get it done like people are like I want
to buy I want to buy it now what do I
need to do but then you're like uh
I don't know like you know you can come
back another time you know you just have
to be straight up it's like you know I
would rather them walk then me not say
anything and them walk out because yeah
when people are in that buying
mode they're going to go on to the next
dealership and they're going to buy a
car yep absolutely that is so
unfortunate well they say statistics are
people usually buy a car within 74 72
hours with hitting their LOB first time
so I mean that's that's a lot that's
that's a high so I mean as soon as they
leave your dealership if they don't
leave in a car I mean the statistics are
you know they're most likely they're not
going to come back so you got to have
the mentality of like they're never
going to come back to your
dealership you know once they leave I
mean some come back obviously but a lot
of times they don't and they go down the
street because they met a Salesman that
they like better or you know they had a
different whatever the case is so you
that's why when they're there you got to
you know you got to treat right
and yeah are you a
workaholic I would say my boss says no
sometimes
but I I my wife definitely says yes I I
I do put in a lot of hours you know
probably 55 maybe 60 hours a week um
which is nothing compared to what you do
Ryan but
uh yeah but so but 50 60 is is a lot and
I and so how do you manage family time
and how does your wife how how does your
wife keep
Saye she um well being a stay-at-home
mom obviously she needs a break from the
um the little guy here and there so yeah
you know having him tug on her all day
long she's like I just need a break so
that's totally un you know totally
understandable working at home all day
but no we um I try to I get to that
we're closed on Sundays in St Lou in
Missouri there's some law we don't have
to be open on Sunday so that's good so
we we're
not day off during the week so you know
and the place that I work at is very
good we get one weekend off a month um
we can take so that's nice most places
you never get any weekends off um so I
work for a really good dealership and
they're very family oriented it's a
family run dealership so it's not a
corporate
run some of these other ones are so
they're they're very sensitive about
family time
mm and yeah and do you say you get
sufficient amount of family time and you
know because the the same thing that you
were afraid of do you ever see yourself
following in your dad's Footsteps in in
that regard or you know cuz what if
there was like What if something became
a like there's a pressing issue where it
required you to not perform as much like
what would you do in that
situation wow I mean it's a good
question i' have to adapt to the
situation um you know move a little bit
and you know get out of my get out of my
borders and see what else is out there
you
know so I
mean I just have
to find another job or you know or find
something that's a little more lowy or
you know even entrepreneurship you know
I can work from home you know well if I
needed to yeah because like if you were
to go on vacation do you lose out on all
those like you know like if uh what
happens when uh like you you have to
take a month off or you got to go on
vacation do you lose all those
sales no so what what happens is if they
come in and they and they ask for you
you automatically we have half deals so
we split deals with sales people so I
come back you know I might have five or
six you know half
deals um but you know yeah you lose all
you lose a lot of sales because
obviously you're not there but you know
you lose a lot of the walk-in traffic
but you don't lose your referrals and
you still don't lose if you set it up
right you can get it set up to where
they'll come back in when you're there
right so that's the good thing so I try
to prepare for that and be like Oh I'm
on vacation this week but I'll be back
next week or two weeks or whatever it is
and they're like oh yeah we want to see
you so we'll wait or whatever it is or
if they have to see somebody else which
is totally cool if they have to buy a
car tomorrow be like go see such go see
my buddy such and such you know he'll
take it care of you because I have a
couple of guys that I use on regular
basis that um you know are very similar
to me yeah where they they'll treat them
right I know they'll treat them right
and that's kind of the the deal that you
gotta have because I mean in business
you have to have good allies right
totally right you got to be able to rely
on you know like what what is your
strategy in in ensuring that you have a
good good
Network um network is is huge and
network is key I mean you know as far as
referral base I go to I go to a local
church here um and um there's a huge
Network at my
church
um and um I I try to utilize utilize
that too those are people that you know
that I love that I do life with you know
on a regular basis and um you
know take good care of
them right and that's a huge Network
there there and then you know just out
and about
meeting people
and so and like how do you keep how do
you get them to like you because I mean
for me it's I'm an introvert like a lot
of people think I'm extroverted I'm
introverted 100% so you know like how
what is your your your tips on on
building those
relationships yeah well the key is just
walk I mean I walk up to people shake
their hand and say hey I'm Scott you
know just just kind of similar to
similar to like how you are when you're
at work yeah you walk up you meet them I
mean some people when they're off or
whatever when they're not in car
sales they just or when you're in car
sales you kind of don't want to you know
talk to a lot of people when you're you
know what I mean just kind of want to
curl up in a ball and not Netbook but
that's where you gotta kind of just go
out there and just shake some hands and
just say hi I'm so and so and you know
just if they have a family or whatever
ask them about their family and then
just and then you know maybe go out to
lunch or maybe go out to dinner maybe
invite them over you know or if you have
a Super Bowl party and have three or
four families you know come over and
kind of get to know them that way on a
personal level because you can't do much
when you're at church but talk for a few
minutes and then go those relationships
really are built
outside you know outside of outside of
church great great so we got a
commercial break so um hang tight if you
can put yourself on mute and then once
uh the commercial is done uh you can put
yourself back or take yourself back off
so a web design company in Calgary is
taking the concept of helping others to
a whole new level and as Robin Crawford
reports it was an Okanagan man who
inspired them to use their Tech skills
to help people with
disabilities it gives me a great
pleasure to introduce to you Michael D
Haynes a motivational speaker an
entrepreneur and a businessman Michael
Haynes is doing it all and I absolutely
love it it's the best job I've ever had
in the beginning Haynes admits that he
didn't know how to get his customer
service Consulting business off the
ground and then he met Ryan Perez with
bow tie creative for every website that
we sell we donate uh free websites to
entrepreneurs with disabilities the
Calgary based company builds websites
for businesses Haynes knew he needed a
website to promote himself self and
Perez knew he had the tools to help we
were always talking about working um um
in the in doing something for the
disability for the for people with
disabilities um but we didn't know what
we were going to do and I thought that
this was a great time to um to do
something and and so we invented this
whole initiative like pretty much around
Michael bow tie creative built and
maintains an entire website for hannes
free of charge he um put my ideas into
action and that made my my
job so much easier oh it's an initiative
that the four-person company is proud of
it's especially close to pere's heart
because he himself has dyslexia I paved
my own path and that's why this this
this project means so much to me because
I want to help other people their paths
bow TI creative is now helping other
people with mental and physical
challenges build websites across North
America all because of Michael Haynes
he's a great guy and it's fantastic
working with him and I can't wait to see
what happens next for him if you know um
anyone that has a mental or physical
disability that wants to become an
entrepreneur or you know needs to needs
help to get started in the right
direction definitely check out our
website haes hopes with the kind of
support offered by Perez and his team
more people will find the confidence to
reach their goals I have a challenge you
have a challenge there not a person
alive without a
challenge
I my challenge is more pronounced than
than yours Robin craford Global News
Colona
hey what's happening everybody coaching
beond with coach sagasta and right now I
want to talk to you real quick man about
the 362 opportunities that you have this
year ahead of you I want you to
definitely optimize on those 362
opportunities create yourself have a
creative process on what you want to
attain this year and be very very
diligent about it if there's anything
I've ever shared with anybody it's about
being diligent and consistent with your
desire to be phenomenal for 2017 as well
as 2018 so get engaged today and don't
waste any more time because despite
despite fear despite the Hobgoblin it is
time to definitely engage at being great
all this year and take every opportunity
to the next level I appreciate your time
coaching beond with Coach sasta I'm out
of here
and we are back okay so we just need to
fix the camera there a little bit it
looks like you're like sinking
down and so we're going to wrap this up
but you know a few questions uh what's
your what's your favorite
movie oh Wall Street Wall Street the
original one that's an amazing movie
yeah I love I can recite every l my wife
hates it when I watch it she's like
would you
[Laughter]
stop what what's your what's the
favorite thing about uh Wall Street that
you would
say Gordon gecko man I just I mean he's
just got the he's just got the killer in
you know Killer Instinct to close I mean
just the overall I think the overall
competition and the sales part of it
just gets me every time movies like that
Boiler Room is probably my second most
favorite movie yeah um you know I just I
just like those type of movies where
people are and the selling and then the
closing and then you know all that you
know aggressiveness stuff I I just love
it yeah would you model yourself at
after any of the
characters um I would probably
say I'm kind of in a mix mixture I'm not
quite Gordon gecko you know what I mean
but um you know Charlie Sheen he's you
know I'm kind of in between there and
Gordon gecko kind of in the middle when
when I'm on when I'm selling when you're
selling yeah when I'm off work I mean
I'm probably like the dad you know just
just hanging out you know just trying to
enjoy my family enjoy my life kind of
thing so yeah what do you like to uh
what do you like to do for
fun wow um we have a lot of we have a
lot of sports here in in St Louis so I
me I like St Louis Blues um hockey um
you probably know a lot about Hockey
being up there in Calgary yeah for
sure but no I'm a Blues fan of course
I'm a St Louis Cardinals baseball fan um
watch their games as much as can um but
mostly just you know playing in the
backyard kicking the soccer ball with
with my son um you know hanging out
doing that kind of stuff that stuff is
just um stuff that time you'll never get
back you know so that that's very
important and uh what's your what's your
favorite
food oh that's a good one I would say
it's a mixture of um mexican and
italian mexican and italian so like if
you had to choose one one gosh I'd
probably say um I'd probably say Italian
Italian are is your parents from Italy
they are not no Germany
unfortunately so what is a what is a
what is a major goal on your bucket
list yeah so I want to go to Bora Bora
Bora Bora why Bora Bora like why all out
all places I want to any one of them
Tiki huts and do absolutely
nothing just just W just look at the
water and just you know just kick back
and relax that that's just I think that
would be amazing a friend of mine went
there and he told me all about it I'm
like oh and I saw see pictures online
all the time like I got I'm gonna go
there yeah are do you like to hike are
you a guy that likes to go out in the
wilderness I do yeah I haven't done it
in a while but my son is that way he
just he wants to go explore and do all
this kind of stuff so I think we're
going to do a little more of that um we
have a lot of places to go camping here
in Missouri obviously being in the
middle of the woods you know in the
country area so you know we'll probably
be doing more of that being two you know
he's hasn't been much into it but now
he's getting a little bit older almost
three so he's wanting to do those kind
of things so yeah for sure and
um what are some lasting Comics that you
want to leave with
everybody well I a couple things I would
say that if you if you want to get in
this business just treat people like
human beings you know treat people as if
they're sitting you know sitting in your
living room having a conversation I mean
that that's the the number one tip that
I can think of and get in with a get in
with a good dealer with a good
reputation that will take care of it if
it takes if they take care of their
employees they're going to take care of
their customers that's pretty much you
know how it is
so and we appreciate all the work you do
out there too with people with
disabilities and things like that Ryan I
mean that I mean that that connected me
you have a heart for that kind of stuff
and um you know we do a lot of stuff at
my church with like missions and you
know things of that nature people that
are you know in other countries that
can't you know provide for themselves
and widows and orphans and things like
that so what you're doing there you know
helping these people out is is
phenomenal oh thank you so much well I
mean you know it's we you know I don't
like even though we promote it via
commercial it's like something that we
don't really talk about just because you
know we're just uh it's just a part like
it's it's my nature to to to help right
it's just it's just a part of my nature
and I got screwed a lot you know helping
certain people and and um throughout the
years and but I was like well I could be
disgruntle and and kind of you know hide
hide my uh light under a bushel basket
or I could just continue to be myself
but just choose you know people uh that
you know that appreciative but also you
know I want to encourage it's not just
you know people with challenges but it's
uh it it's um just encouraging people to
be entrepreneurs yeah encouraging people
just to hustle like showing them that
every day like I mean my my life is a
little bit obsessive I mean like the the
the things that I do here I'm pretty
obsessed of what I because I I I I do
have Big Dreams however you know even if
you just put an hour or
two you know you put an hour or two into
in into something that is yours right
you know it makes a difference so we
just want to help people get to the to
to the next level in our in our lives
you know what I mean absolutely yeah I
mean thinking outside the box you know
doing that kind of stuff you know
they're life is so short you know don't
just go out and go out and get what you
want go out and get what's
there you
know so so yeah I I appreciate you
coming in so how do we find you yeah I'm
at um Dave Sinclair Ford in um St Louis
we're about 10 minutes from um downtown
most people associate St Louis obviously
with the arch or Bush Stadium or or
something like that but we're just in
the suburbs there um Dave Sinclair
ford.com or you can come see me at Dave
Sinclair Ford um Lindberg and liem May
Ferry awesome and um this my favorite
part of the show because before we leave
you know I do a little something and
then you do a little something so do you
know what I'm talking
about
um no I'm gonna ask you to I'm going to
do a call and
response uh I'm gonna say welcome to the
and I need you to scream it as loud as
you can the hustle
Zone got it okay so welcome to
the hustle Zone
[Laughter]
nice thank you so much
uhan Scott you know I I really
appreciate you coming in uh to to the
hustle Zone and uh and I I hope I know
that we're going to work together some
in in some capacity soon very much so we
are going to work together yeah for sure
so thank you so much and have a good day
uh folks thank you guys all for for
joining into the hustle Zone make sure
you guys watch this one again you know
Co entrepreneurs and the entrepreneur
IAL mindset it comes
in in so many different forms we're all
different people but we have similar
habits you know the key thing about
selling yourself and making that money
is the relationship that's what Scott is
saying it like he's not telling you any
fancy closing tricks or any anything
like that he's telling you to build
relationships a lot of us get onto
social media first thing we do is we hit
the person up like especially you multi
multi marketers you guys come to me and
like hey are you happy with your life of
course I am you know don't you see the
hustle Zone every day I'm not here you
know just uh kicking tires right uh so I
I I would be interested in looking at
what you have but you know you got to
become my friend first I'm not going to
just do business with you not knowing
you and so the whole thing is like we
you know we want to build those
relationships with those key people
networking is key in this business
especially for a guy like Scott because
the relationships are all his whole
business is built on the
relationship because if he doesn't build
those relationships when people are
deciding to get into a new car again
they're going to go elsewhere yeah right
you know they're going to go elsewhere
because they don't have any ties to you
one thing I learned in the car business
was at you know if they don't trust you
they don't like you why would they
recommend their friend friends to you
why would they recommend their family to
you you know why would they recommend
their Community to you they're not you
know so the key thing is followup you
know is isn't that right Scott followup
you know just calling people seeing how
they're doing sending out birthday cards
like that stuff is a lot of
work yeah you got to keep your name out
in front of them though otherwise
they'll forget it you know like give you
know go out for coffee build
relationships with some of them like it
you know you got to work your business
it's just like social media you got got
to work this game you know it's all this
stuff is hard work and then when you
have that funnel that comes through it
you know everything kind of equalizes
itself out after that so you know right
folks you know it was Scott it was a
pleasure having you around and and we
got a lease uh we got a lease with being
nice matters on tomorrow and again if
you guys are interested in joining
joining the um the hustle Zone fitness
challenge and if you want to participate
or you want to
volunteer um or you want to give some
advice because I don't know what I'm
doing 100% so um I don't really want to
run this by myself I kind of want to run
it with some people so if you guys do
know someone that wants to be a part of
this group please hit me up and uh thank